Rabo Yusuf

$\underline{raboyusuf94@gmail.com} \mid \underline{\textbf{LinkedIn}} \mid \underline{\textbf{Github}} \mid \underline{\textbf{Portfolio}}$

SUMMARY

With extensive experience in Software Engineering, I possess a deep understanding of various technologies such as JavaScript, TypeScript, React, Redux, CSS, Python, PyTorch, scikit-learn, math, probability, statistics, algorithms, and HTML. I have hands-on experience in user interface design and have worked on large-scale projects where I applied my knowledge in JavaScript, React.js, Node.js, Webpack, Redux, Jest, and React Testing Library, math, probability, statistics, algorithms, Python, PyTorch, sci-kit-learn. I prioritize performance, accessibility, and application design, ensuring my work meets high standards. Additionally, I excel in communicating technical concepts to non-technical stakeholders.

SOFT SKILLS:

- Communication
- Teamwork
- Time Management
- Collaboration

EXPERIENCE:

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

The Bulb Africa

April 2021 – Present

- Demonstrated experience with user interface design by developing responsive designs that prioritize accessibility and user experience.
- Applied my expertise as a Web Developer to create complex and interactive web applications that integrate with back-end systems.
- Possess knowledge of JavaScript libraries and tools including React.js, Webpack, Enzyme, Redux, Material UI, Chakra and Flux to manage complex projects and optimize performance.

• Developed a RESTful API using NodeJS and Express, which improved the performance of the web application by 30% and reduced the response time by 50%.

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Colab Tech

Jan 2019 – March 2021

- Wrote readable, logically sound, and well-documented JavaScript code while following established coding standards and best practices.
- Demonstrated empathy with the many different types of users who use UI, and effectively solved problems through careful consideration of product requirements.
- Deeply care about performance, accessibility, and application design to ensure a topquality product.
- Proficient in communicating technical concepts to non-technical stakeholders through clear and concise language.

EDUCATION:

Masters in Engineering (Energy, CGPA 4.38)

April 2015 – Aug 2018

Bayero University Kano.

CERTIFICATION:

Nano Degree in React, Redux, and React Native

July 2021 – Dec 2021

Udacity United States of America